Guide to the New York State Teachers Association Records 1915-1979
New York State Teachers Association Records
- Series III: Executive Secretary's Files
  - Sub-Series C: Goold Subject Files, 1950-1971, 1950-1971
    - Sub-Series b: Legislation
      - L-Principals' Salaries-Correspondence (2) 1966 (Box 33, Folder 45)
      - Principals' Salary Law., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 46)
        Contains a bill re salary increases for school principals.1966
      - Requests for Principal's Salary Law. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 47)
      - L-State University Salaries. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 48)
      - L-Teacher's Salary Differentials 5th and 6th Years., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 49)
        Contains copies of the act. 1966
      - L-Teachers' Salary, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 50)
        Differentials-Memos. Contains cost estimates of career increments and salary differentials along with a memo re minimum salary for teachers with preparation beyond the 5th or 6th year. 1966
      - L-Teachers' Salary-Career Increments-Memos. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 51)
      - L-Career Increments-Working Papers., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 52)
        Contains a memo re the cost of resolutions re career increments and salary differentials. 1966
      - Minimum Salary (Box 33, Folder 53)
        Contains the bill and memo with salary schedule data, and interpretation of the Minimum Salary Statute (Annual Increments), and cases involving denial of promotional increment study credits. (Miller, Goldman, and Jacobs vs. Board of Education of the City School District of NYC Also contains median salary data and a summary of the 1962 Teacher' Salary Law. 1966-69
      - L-Summary of the Effects of the Minimum Salary Law, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 54)
        Contains the act and memo re minimum salary for teachers with preparation beyond the 5th or the year, as well as the summary. 1966
      - L-Extended School Year., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 55)
        Contains a copy of NYS Education, a pamphlet re the economy and increased opportunity through an extended school year programs, a study of the implications of the program, and a statement by the president of NYSTA re the proposal. 1966
      - Clippings-School Year Study. 1963, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 56)
      - L-State Aid., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 57)
        Contains a bill and memo re apportionment of funds to school districts. Also contains a memo re supplemental School Aid Bill, and the report of the NYS Edcational conference Board. General correspondence is also included. 1966
      - L-State Aid, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 58)
        contains a bill and memo re apportionment of funds to school districts. Also contains a memo re supplemental School Aid Bill and the report of the NYS Educational Conference Board. General correspondence is also included. 1966
      - State Aid., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 59)
        Contains budget information for the Ramapo Central School District, a news release re the Dominick- Knottler Bill, plus an analysis of New York State School Aid Correction. Also contains the bill dealing with apportionment, and a report on equal opportunity as adopted by the House of Delegates, resolutions of NEA on Urban Educational Problems, desegregation and fair housing, data pertinent to state aid, and Goold's statement to members of the committee to revise and simplify the Education law are also included. 1966-67
      - Legislation-State Aid-Current Year Expense, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 60)
        Contains a bill and memo re apportionment of public moneys to school districts employing eight or more teachers. 1966
      - L-State Aid-Burke Memos, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 61)
        Contains a draft of the size correction bill, and a memo re the statutory tax rate. 1966
      - State Aid-Personal., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 62)
        Contains memos re state aid and alternate proposals. 1966
      - Legislation-State Aid for Summer Schools and Adult Education, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 63)
        General correspondence. 1966
      - Legislation-superannuation Memo. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 64)
      - Analysis of the Provision of the Taylor Committee Bill. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 65)
      - 1965 Teacher-School Board Relations Bill. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 66)
      - L-Bill-Teacher-School Board Relations (Box 33, Folder 67)
        Comtaoms a no;; re the si[ervosopm nu the Board of Regnets of professional organizations of teachers.1966
      - L-Bulletin re Teacher-School Board Relations. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 68)
      - L-Clips, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 69)
        Teacher-School Board Relations. 1966
      - L-Correspondence- Teacher School Board Relations., 1966 (Box 33, Folder 70)
        Contains a bill on Public Employee Labor Rights as well as general correspondence. 1966
      - Teacher-School Board Relations, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 71)
        (Education Department's Position on Taylor) Contains the Taylor Bill with a memo outlining the reasoning behind the support of the Taylor Committee Report with modification. 1966
      - L-Memo-Teacher-School Board Relations, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 72)
        Contains a bill and memo dealing with the supervision by the Board of Regents of professional organizations of teachers. 1966
      - L-Teacher-School Board Relations, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 73)
        Contains a billl and memo dealing with the Rose-Dominick Bills. 1966
      - L-Teacher-School Board Relations Opposition Memos, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 74)
        Contains memos from the UFT. 1966
      - L-Teacher-School Board Relations-Working Papers, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 75)
        Contains a bill and memos re t he duties of school authorities and the Board of Regents with respect to teachers. Also contains information on plans for school board- teacher relation in Great Neck and California. 1966
      - Legislation-Textbook Law, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 76)
        Contains the textbook act and a memo from the associate commissioner for Education Finance and Management Services, re compliance with the law. 1966
      - Legislation-Vocational Education, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 77)
        Contains an act re continuation of vocational and special education in the county of Nassau and a pamphlet re cooperative educational services. 1966.
      - Legislators' Voting Record. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 78)
      - Legislation-Yonkers Endorsement of Certain Bills, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 79)
        Contains clarification of provision of the Text Book Law. 1966
      - Legislation-General (Clippings, etc.) 1966 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - L-ACCES, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        Contains a pamphlet re cooperative educational services. 1966
      - L-BOCES, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        Contains a bill re construction and funding of cooperative education services. 1966
      - L-Hearings, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 4)
        Contains memo and news clippings re the state budget. 1967
      - L-Bulletins and Wires-Special. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - L-Commissioner of Education-To Limit Power of Review Board. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Committee of 100,000., 1967 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        General correspondence. 1967
      - L-Conference Days., 1967 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        Contains memo and bill re conditions under which districts are entitled to apportionment. 1967
      - L-Conference Days-Memos, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 9)
        Contains the memo re apportionment of funds to school districts. 1967
      - Constitutional Convention-Labor, Civil Service, Pensions Committee, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        Contains summaries of proposition introduced, the statement of Goold to the committee, and various propositions re wages, work, civil service appointment, membership in public pension and retirement s systems, and taxation of compensation of public officers and disciplinary proceedings to employees in the civil service, and the right to organize and bargain collectively, workmen's compensation, and a labor bill of rights. Contains the rules of the 1967 constitutional convention. 1967
      - Constitutional Convention (Booklets, Documents, etc.), 1967 (Box 34, Folder 11)
        Contains the NYS Constitution (amended to 1/1/67) the proposed constitution, the rules of the'67 convention, an analysis of proposals affecting education which might come before the convention, the recommendations of the NYS Educational conference Board to the convention, an analysis of the proposed NYS Constitution, and the text, abstract, and highlights of the proposed constitution. 1967
      - L-Copies Sent To NYSTA of Correspondence to Legislators, From Members, and Other Organizations., 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 12)
        Contains a letter from the Director of Public Education Association re the need for an increased budget, plus the statement of the Superintendent of NYC Schools, Re State financing of public education. 1967-68
      - Priser Education.1967 (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - Educational Conference Board, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 14)
        Contains news release re amendment of the state aid formula. 1967
      - L-Gun Control Legislation, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 15)
        Contains bills re possession of rifles and shotguns, the licensing of dealers in rifles and shotguns, and the sales of ammunition, also contains an article by Adlai Stevenson's III and a Reader's Digest article re gun control. General correspondence also included. 1967
      - L-Civil Service Law, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 16)
        re Health Insurance for Retirees of School Districts. Contains a memo and bill re the above. 1967
      - Health Insurance Memo, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 17)
        Contains memo re requirement that school authorities provide a health insurance plan for employees and their dependents. 1967
      - Other Health Insurance Bills, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 18)
        Contains bill re employee contributions under the state health insurance plan. 1967
      - Proposed and Final Legislative Program, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 19)
        Contains various proposed legislation, the 1967 legislative program, and highlights of the legislative year. 1967
      - Association-Proposed Legislative Program, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 20)
        Working Papers. Contains various memos re proposed legislation. 1967
      - L-Miscellaneous., 1967 (Box 34, Folder 21)
        Contains bills re the organization of the city school district in NYC, and employer contributions under the state health insurance plan. 1967
      - August 2nd-Meeting with Dr. Helsby, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 22)
        Contains the Taylor Act, selections from the NLRA and representation procedures. 1967
      - L-Minimum Wages-Federal and State Requirements., 1967 (Box 34, Folder 23)
        Contains a memo re Federal Fair Labor Standards Act, and the New York Minimum Wage Act. 1967
      - L-Music, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 24)
      - Professional Negotiations, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 25)
        Materials Used at Workshops. Contains sample agreement with negotiation aids. 1967-68
      - NYSTA Staff Negotiations Procedures, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 26)
        Contains a guide for field representatives, memos on staff organization and operation procedures, election strategy and application of pressure. Also contains a negotiation digest. 1967
      - NYS Public Employment Relations Board (General), 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 27)
        Contains the partial report and recommendations of counsel in regard to NYSTA vs. Helsby et al (PERB) the preliminary guidelines for local public employers and employee organizations on the Taylor law, a memo outlining the provisions of the public employees, fair employment act, and a pamphlet dealing with PERB. 1967-68
      - PERB-Newspaper Clippings. 1967-69, 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 28)
      - PERB-Public Hearings, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 29)
        Contains a statement made by Goold in support of modification in the draft rules of the Employment Relations Board. 1967
      - PERB-Publications: Guidelines, Questions and Answers, Rules. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 30)
      - PERB-Rules and Regulations, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 31)
        Contains a statement of procedures under the public employees' fair employment act, and a copy of the draft rules with correspondence from counsel re the act, plus a brief supporting modification in the draft rules of the public employment relations board. 1967
      - L-Bill-Public School Support, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 32)
        Contains the bill re the apportionment of public moneys to school districts. 1967
      - L-Regional Supplemental Education Centers, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 33)
        Contains the bill and memo re supplemental educational centers plus a project proposed for a Title III operational grant for a career line training program of semi-professionals in education (West Genesee Central School and Camillus Central School District) 1967
      - L-Resolutions Which Require Legislative Action, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 34)
        Contains a full text of resolutions approved by the House of Delegates in 1966. 1967
      - L-Retirement Bills, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 35)
        Contains bill and memo re the establishment of non-contributory retirement plans and death benefits for members of NYS Teachers Retirement System. 1967
      - L-Retirement Bill, Amended. 1967, 1967-1967 (Box 34, Folder 36)
      - Memo., 1967 (Box 34, Folder 37)
        Contains memo dealing with the establishment of non-contributory retirement plans and death benefits for members of the NYS Teachers Retirement system. 1967
      - Working Papers, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 38)
        Contains memo and bill re non-contributory retirement plans and death benefits. Also contains a retirement bulletin and an estimate on the value of retirement allowance after 30 years. 1967
      - L-Retirement-Cost-of-Living Retirement Benefit Bills, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 39)
        Contains the bill and correspondence with comptroller Levitt re cost of living retirement benefits. 1967
      - L-Memo-Disability and Deferred Retirement Death Benefits. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 40)
      - Legislation-General Special Memo re Retirement Elections. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 41)
      - L-Retirement Election Bill. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 42)
      - L-Retirement Elections-Papers, 1967-1967 (Box 34, Folder 43)
        Contains bill and original drafts re retirement elections. 1967
      - L-Retirement Bills-Memos to get Two of Mr. Crawford's Bills Out of Committee (Box 34, Folder 44)
        Contains memos re contributions by member of the NYST Retirement System, and special service retirement. 1967
      - L-Retirement 1/60th Plan-Cr. Briand, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 45)
        Contains the bill and correspondence related to the 1/60th plan. 1967
      - L-Retirement-Repayment of Loans by Payroll Deduction, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 46)
      - Bulletin re Special Service (early) Retirement and the 1/120th Reopening-Working Papers. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 47)
      - Legislation-Roll Call Votes, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 48)
        Contains the votes on the Taylor Bill, the Coop Board Bill, the Variable Annuity Bill, the Health Insurance Bill, the Lottery, the Protection of Tenure Bill, and the cost of Living Supplemental Pension Bill, 1967
      - L-Principals' Salaries., 1967 (Box 34, Folder 49)
        Contains a bill and general correspondence re minimum salaries for principals. 1967
      - L-Principals' Salary Bills and Memos Prepared for John L. French, Great Neck. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 50)
      - L-Bill-Teachers' Salaries, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 51)
        Also contains a memo re minimum salaries for teachers. 1967
      - Memo, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 52)
        Contains the act re minimum salary for teachers
      - L-Unused Sick Leave, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 53)
        Contains act and memo re health insurance premiums. 1967
      - L-Duryea State Aid Bill, 1967-1967 (Box 34, Folder 54)
        Also contains a memo re the bill. 1967
      - Clippings-State Aid. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 55)
      - Working Papers, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 56)
        Contains tax rates of schools in Nassau county. 1967
      - L-State Aid for Depressed Districts, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 57)
        Contains a bill dealing with apportionment of funds to school districts. Also contains the statement and resolutions of Senator Giuffreda and Speno. 1967
      - State Education Department, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 58)
        PERB Hearing, Conferences, etc. 1967
      - L-Taylor Committee Bill (general), 1967 (Box 34, Folder 59)
        Contains the Bill with a memo from the Governor, representation procedure, the final report of the 1966 Committee on Public Employee Relations (1966), and the opinion of Counsel of the State Education Department on the Taylor Law. 1967
      - L-Taylor Bill-Reactionists, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 60)
        Contains newspaper clippings. 1967
      - Taylor Law-Meeting, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 61)
      - Taylor Act-Primer. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 62)
      - L-Bill, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 63)
        Teacher school board relations. 1967
      - L-Revised Teacher-School Board Relations Bill, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 64)
        Contains general correspondence and a bill to grant to public employees the right of organization and representation for the purpose of bargaining collectively. 1967
      - Clippings-Teacher-School Board Relations. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 65)
      - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 66)
        Contains a copy of the Professional Negotiation agreement in District No. 2, Uniondale, and a copy of the Indiana School Board's Association Resolution on Teacher-School Board Negotiations. 1967
      - Memo, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 67)
        Re the supervision by the Board of Regents of professional organizations of teachers. 1967
      - Working Papers, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 68)
        Contains Teacher-School Board Relations Memo. 1967
      - Budget Bills Passed in Legislature, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 1)
        Contains the Local Assistance Budget Bill. 1968
      - Budget Hearings, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 2)
        Contains a news release re Mrs. Barrett's statement at the 1968-69 local assistance budget hearing. Also contains her statement at the New York State Local Assistance Budget for 1968-70. 1968
      - L-Buffalo Income Tax-Rules Bill. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Candidates for Legislature. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - L-Interstate Certification, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 5)
        Contains a pamphlent, and memo re the interestate certification project, 1968
      - L-Maximum Class Size, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        Contains an act and memo re grants to school districts in order to reduce class size 1968.
      - L-Comment and Reactions, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 7)
        Contains correspondence re operating expenses. 1968
      - L-Educations Conference Board (State Aid), 1968 (Box 35, Folder 8)
        Contains an act and memo re appropriation of funds to school districts. Also contains a memo with data pertinent to need for state aid increases. 1968
      - L-Election and/or Lobby Expenses, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        Contains general correspondence. 1968
      - L-Mandatory Health Insurance, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 10)
        Contains memo and bill re health insurance. 1968
      - Legislative Program, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 11)
        Contains the legislative record and a description and summary of that program. 1968
      - L-Clippings. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - L-NYSTA Proposed, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 13)
        Contains general correspondence, the 1968 legislative program, and the minimum salary proposal. 1968
      - Letters to Governor Rockefeller, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 14)
        In Support of Legislation. 1968
      - List of Legislators-Senators and Assemblymen. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - L-Lottery., 1968-1968 (Box 35, Folder 16)
        Contains the Lottery Bill and correspondence and memos re the lottery. 1968
      - NY City Transit Bill. (Re retirement). 1968 (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - PERB Impasse, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 18)
        Contains a memo re declaration of an impasse. 1968
      - Governor's Conference on PERB. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Governor's Committee of Public Employee Relations, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 20)
        Interim Report. Contains the interim report plus recommendations. 1968
      - Meeting with PERB-Oct. 1, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 21)
        General correspondence. 1968
      - PERB-Streiff Speech at Baltimore. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 22)
      - Resolutions Approved by the House of Delegates, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 23)
        Contains a full text of resolutions as reached by the House of Delegates. 1968
      - L-J. Interest on Contributions, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 24)
        Contains a bill and memo re interest. 1968
      - L-Military Service Credit, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 25)
        Contains a bill and memo re the above. 1967
      - Non-Contributory Retirement Plan (Compromise Version), 1968 (Box 35, Folder 26)
        contains the bill and memo re the retirement plan. General correspondence also included. 1968
      - L-Retirement (Non-Contributory), 1968 (Box 35, Folder 27)
        Contains an outline of the bill, the bill itself, and a memo. General correspondence also included. 1968
      - NYS Teachers' Retirement System, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 28)
        2% Non-Contributory Bill. Contains the bill and various memos. Also includes opposition memo of AFT, news releases, and the report of the retirement Board and general correspondence. 1968
      - Final Revised Version of Retirement Bill, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 29)
        Contains an act and general correspondence re the non-contributory retirement bill. Also contains AFT opposition memo. 1968
      - New Legislation-Retirement Simplification and Modernization. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 30)
      - Legislation-Roll call Vote, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 31)
        Contains the votes on the retirement bill, state aid, variable annuity, supplemental pensions, judgeships, and interest rates. 1968
      - L-Minimum Salary, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 32)
        Contains the minimum salary bill and memoranda. Also contains general data on teachers salaries and operating expenses, a history of teacher minimum salary legislation, the dollar amounts for teacher minimum salary proposals for various school districts, a report on school district expenditures, comparison of teachers' salaries and other occupations. 1968
      - Final Bill-Minimum Salary, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 33)
        Contains the bill and memo. Also contains general correspondence. 1968
      - L-Supplemental Pension, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 34)
        Contains the bill, explanatory memo, and general correspondence. 1968
      - L-Unused Sick Leave. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 35)
      - L-Public School Support (State Aid), 1968 (Box 35, Folder 36)
        Contains apportionment bills with amendments, a description of high tax aid formulas, and data on the state fiscal situation. 1968
      - State Aid-Clippings. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 37)
      - Kheel report on Taylor Law. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 38)
      - L-Tenure, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 39)
        Contains the tenure bill and memo. 1968
      - Tenure Bill, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 40)
        Contains the bill with a section by section analysis. 1968
      - L-Transportation bond Issue., 1968 (Box 35, Folder 41)
        Contains general correspondence, pamphlets, and gubernatorial addresses re the bond issue. 1968
      - L-Variable Annuity, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 42)
        Contains the bill with an analysis and explanation of the bill's operation. Also includes a memo to the Governor. 1968
      - L-Variable Annuity, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 43)
        Contains the 1968 bill with memo and the 1967 bill, a pamphlet dealing with variable annuity, and and explanatory letter to Dr. Brind (counsel to the Dept./ of Education) re variable annuity. Also contains a draft bill wit revisions 1968
      - L-Voting Record on Various Bills. 1968 (Box 35, Folder 44)